In the previous lesson, we introduced you to this concept of functions.
So basically Python has a whole lot of functions that we can use.
And like we said, print is actually a function.
But in order for you to use a function you have to know its name.
So obviously we could never have used print if we didn't know that print existed.
So how do we do this?
And how do we remember what functions work with what and what their names are and all things to do with
functions basically.
So like I also said in one of our earlier lessons, Python documentation is very important.
So you can see here I am in the path and documentation at the moment.
And you can just Google path documentation or go straight to this link and it will come up with this
page.
Now what this page is basically is it is a list of well, a whole lot of things.
But inside this you will see there are these things called modules.
Okay.
Now what is a module.
So like I said earlier, functions where functions for everything, basically, uh, and they are very
important.
Now in order to find functions and make it more and make them more easier to use, we split them up
into various modules.
So basically here you see there is this module called well there's numeric and mathematical modules.
So if I wanted a function to do with let's say maths I would need to go to the maths module.
Okay.
So you'll see I'm now inside a maths module.
And this module will store all functions to do with math.
Okay.
So let's go down and look at some of them as an example.
So remember before how we had uh we tried to find something to the power of something and we actually
used this.
We use this a, a number to the power of another number.
So it could go ten to the power of two.
But instead of doing that, we can actually use this thing over here.
We can say math which is the name of the module uses thing called a dot operator.
And then we use this name.
Okay, this might look a bit different to the way we use print because we don't have this dot.
And what is all of this.
But we're going to look at examples of these all in the future lectures.
But for now, what I need you to remember is that we have a whole lot of functions which can do and
work out, uh, things for us and make our life much easier.
Like, you can see, if you want to work out log instead of doing it, uh, by yourself, you can just
use these.
And, I mean, if you go through these, you'll see especially.
Well, this is a maths module.
So you'll see it's all to do with maths.
Okay.
So basically what I was saying you need to remember that we have modules and modules store functions
of similar types.
So that was a mathematical module.
I mean we have different data types.
They are all modules.
So look at these.
Look at the different modules.
And you know you can see how certain functions are all inside certain modules.
So yeah that's it for now.
And we are going to go and look at examples in our next lesson.